In this segment, we're going to construct
two classic MACS, the CBC-MAC and the
这一节，我们将构造两个经典的MAC，CBC-MAC和
NMAC. Recall in the last segment, we said
that if you give me a secure PRF, then
NMAC。回忆上一节，我们说如果你给我一个安全的PRF，那么
that secure PRF can actually be used to
construct a secure MAC, simply by defining
这个安全的PRF可以用来构造一个安全的MAC，就是简单
the signature on the message m as the
value of the function at the point m. The
地定义对消息m的签名是这个消息m的函数
only caveat was that the output of the
PRF F had to be large. For example, it
唯一的需要注意的是PEF的F函数输出必须足够大 比如 它
could be 80 bits or 128 bits, and that
would generate a secure MAC Now we also
必须是80或者128比特的，可以生成一个安全的MAC 现在我们
said that because AES is a secure PRF,
essentially AES already gives us a secure
说因为AES是一个安全的PRF，基本上AES已经给我们安全的
MAC, except that it can only process
sixteen byte messages. And the question
MAC了，除了它只能处理16字节的消息。现在问题
now is, given a PRF for short messages
like AES for sixteen byte messages, can we
是，给出一个像AES这样有16字节的短消息PRF，我们
construct a PRF for long messages that are
potentially gigabytes long? And this is
能构造出一个PRF可以处理可能G比特的数据吗？
shorthand for what's coming. I'm going to
denote by X, the set  to the N where N
把这个作为简写 我在这里用X表示，集合01n其中n是
is the block size for the underlying PRF.
So since we're always going to be thinking
内在PRF的分组大小 因为我们总是要考虑AES
of AES as the underlying PRF, you can
think of N as essentially 128 bits. So
作为内在PRF，你可以认为n就是128比特
the first construction is called the
encrypted CBC MAC, or ECBC for short.
第一种构造称为加密的CBC-MAC，或者简写为ECBC
Encrypted CBC MAC. So ECBC uses a PRF that
takes messages in the set X  to the N
加密的CBC MAC。因此ECBC以01n集合X中的消息为输入
and outputs messages in the same set X.
And what we're going to be building is a
输出消息也在集合X中。我们将要构造的
PRF that basically takes pairs of keys. It
takes very long messages, in fact
PRF基本上需要成对的密钥 消息很长 实际上
arbitrarily long messages, and I'll
explain this in just a second and it
是任意长的消息 后面我会解释
outputs also tags in  to the N. So
that's our goal. Now what is this X to the
它的输出也是01n集合中的元素 也就是我们的结果 现在问题是
less than or equal to L? The point here is
that in fact CBC MAC can take very long
X和L比是短了还是相等？这里的关键是 实际上CBC MAC可以取最多
messages up to L blocks. L could be a
million or a billion. But it could also
L块长度的消息 L 可能是一百万或一兆,也有可能
take variable length messages as inputs.
In other words, X less than or equal to L
以变化长度的消息作为输入 换句话说 X是小于等于L的
means that we allow the input to be
messages that contain an arbitrary number
意味着我们允许的消息有任意长的分组，
of blocks between one and L. So each CBC
can process messages that are one block
在1和L之间。每一个CBC可以处理消息的长度可以使1个分组
long, two blocks long, ten blocks long,
100 blocks long. It's perfectly fine to
2个分组，10个分组或100个分组等等 输入大小完全没问题
give it variable size inputs. But just to
keep the discussion simple, we up our
但是为了讨论简单起见，我们把上限定为
bounds the maximum length by capital L. So
let's see how ECBC works. Well, we start
大写L。现在我们看看ECBC是怎么工作的，好
by taking our message and breaking it into
blocks, each block is as long as a block
我们从消息开始，把消息分组，每组的长度就是内置函数F的
of the underlying function f, and then
essentially we run through the CBC chain
分组长度，接着我们把CBC链过一遍
except that we don't output intermediate
values. So you notice we basically encrypt
但我们不输出中间值 你会注意到 我们基本上就是加密了
the first block and then feed the results
into the XOR with the second block and
第一个分组，把加密结果与第二个分组进行异或后
then feed that into f again, and we do
that again and again and again and finally
然后再用F处理，我们一遍接一遍的做，直到最后我们
we get a value out here. Which is called
the CBC outputs of this long chain. And
得到这个结果，称作CBC这个长链输出
then, I would like to point your attention
to the fact that we do one more encryption
接着，我想让大家注意一下，我们实际上进行了另一个
step. And this step is actually done using
an independent key, K1. That's different
加密步骤，这个步骤实际上使用了一个独立的密钥k1，这个密钥
and chosen independently of the key K, and
finally the output gives us the tag. So in
和密钥k的选取互相独立，最后这个输出是标签
this case the tag would be N bits long,
but we also mentioned in the previous
这种情况下，标签式N比特长的，但是我们在前面的章节也提到了
segment that it's fine to truncate the tag
to less than N bits long as long as one
把标签截断短至N比特以下和？？？
over two to the end is negligible. So now
you can see that FECBC takes a pair of
是可以忽略的。所以我们现在看到Fecbc以一对密钥
keys as inputs, it can process
variable length messages and it produces
作为输入，它可以处理长度为变量的消息生成
an output in the set X. So you might be
wondering what this last encryption step
的输出属于集合X。所以你现在可能会疑惑这个最后一个加密
is for. And I'll tell you that the
function that's defined without this last
是为什么 我告诉你这个函数，如果没有最后这个
encryption step is called the raw CBC
function. In other words, if we simply
加密步骤，称之为 raw CBC（简化）函数。换句话说，如果我们
stop processing over here, and we take
that as the output, that's called raw CBC.
仅在这里就停了，以这个作为输出，就称为简化CBC
And as we'll see in a minute, raw CBC is
actually not a secure MAC. So this last
等一下我们会看到，这个简化CBC不是一个安全的MAC 所以这个最后一步
step is actually critical for making
the MAC secure. So another class of
实际上对构造一个安全的MAC是很重要的。另外一种把小规模
construction for converting a small PRF
into a large PRF is called NMAC,
PRF转换为大规模PRF构造MAC的方式称为NMAC
for Nested MAC. Now, the NMAC starts
from PRF that, as before, takes inputs
是为网状MAC。NMAC也是从PRF开始，像前面一样
in X, but outputs elements in the key
space. And remember that for CBC, the
输入为集合X重元素，但是输出是在密钥空间K。回忆前面的CBC
output has to be in the set X. Here, the
output needs to be in the key space K. And
输出必须在集合X中。这里输出在密钥空间K
again, we basically obtain the PRF F-NMAC, which takes pairs of keys as inputs.
这个基本上就是我们的FNMAC PRF了，它以两对密钥为输入
Again, can process variable length
messages up until L blocks. And the output
也能处理长度为L组以下的消息，输出是
is an element in the key space. And the
way NMAC works is kind of, starts as
密钥空间的一个元素，NMAC工作的方式，和
before. We take our message, and we break
it into blocks. Each block is, again, as
前面的类似。我们把消息分组，每个分组，和前面一样
big as the block length of the underlying
PRF. And now we take our key and we feed
和内置PRF的分组长度一样，现在我们把密钥作为函数
our key as the key input into the function
F. And the message block is given as the
F的密钥输入 这个消息分组也作为这个函数F
data input into the function F. What comes
out is the key for the next block of NMAC.
的输入 输出作为下一组NMAC的密钥
So now we have a new key for the next
evaluation of the PRF. And the data for
所以现在对这个PRF的下一组消息我们有了个新密钥，以此类推
the next evaluation is the next message
block and so on and so forth until we
对下一个消息进行函数变换，直到
reach the final output. The final output
is gonna be an element in K. Okay? And
我们得到最后的输出，最后的输出会是一个K中的元素，对吧？
just as before, in fact, if we stop here.
The function that we obtain is called a
和前面一样，实际上，如果我们这里就停了。这个函数我们称为
cascade function. And we're gonna look at
cascade in more detail in just a minute.
级联函数，我们再回来看一下这个级联
So cascade will output an element in K.
However, that, as we'll see again, is not
级联函数会输出一个K中的元素，但是，我们会看到，这不是
a secure MAC. To get a secure MAC, what we
do is we need to map this element T,
一个安全的MAC。为了获得安全的MAC，我们需要把这个
which is in K, into the set X. And so,
typically, as we'll see, NMAC is used
K中的元素t，映射到X中。基本上，我们会看到，NMAC
with, PRFs, where the block length, X, is
much bigger than the key length. And so
用到这些PRF，分组长度X要比密钥长度长得多。
what we do is we simply append fixed pad.
fpad is called a fixed pad that gets
就简单的固定填充就行。fpad称为固定填充，
appended to this tag T. And then this
becomes, this input here, this block here
就是对标签T附加些信息。然后这里，这个输入这里，这个分组
becomes an element of X. We feed this into
the function, and again, notice here that
成了了X中的元素，我们把这个输入给函数，再一次，
there's an independent key that's being
used for the last encryption step. And
注意到这里是一个独立的密钥，在最后一次加密中使用
then finally, the last tag is an element
of K which we output as the output of
最后，最后这个标签式一个K中的一个元素，我们作为NMAC的输出
NMAC. So remember without the last
encryption step, the function is called a
记住，如果没有最后这个加密步骤，这个函数称为
cascade. With the last step as we'll see
which is necessary for security, we
级联函数。有这个步骤，后面我们会看到对安全性来说是必要的，我们
actually get a PRF which outputs elements
in K, and can process variable length
得到了一个PRF，输出是K中的元素，可以处理变长度
messages that are up to L blocks long.
Alright so that is the NMAC
的消息，长度最长可到L个分组。好了，这就是NMAC
construction. So now we have two MACs. That
we can use to build a large PRF, from AES,
的构造。现在我们有了两个MAC。我们可以用AES来构造大型的PRF
basically. So before I analyze the
security of MAC constructions, I'd like
前面，我分析过了MAC的安全性，我希望
you to understand better what the last
encryption step is for. So, let's start
你们能更好地理解最后一步加密是为了什么。好，让我们从NMAC开始。
with NMAC. So I explained that it
is actually very easy too see that if we
这个我解释起来实际上很容易知道，如果我们
omitted the last encryption step. In other
words, if we just use the cascade
省掉了最后一步加密，换句话说，如果我们只用这个
function, then the MAC will be completely
insecure. Okay so suppose we look at this
级联函数，MAC就完全不安全了，好，现在假设我们来
MAC to find over here. In other words, all
we do is we output directly the cascade
看一下这个MAC的问题。也就是说，我们做的就是直接从这个级联
applied to m without the last encryption
step. So let me ask you how do you forge
输出m的结果，不用最后一步加密。我问一下，你怎么能复制出一个标签？
tags in this MAC. And I guess I've kinda
given it away that this answer isn't
在这个MAC中。我想我基本上帮你把这个答案排除掉
correct. So I hope everybody sees that the
answer is, that, in fact, given one chosen
正确。我希望每个人都选这个答案，实际上，给定一个
message query, you can mount an
existential forgery. And the reason is,
选择消息质询，你可以构造一个存在伪造。原因是
I'll show you in a second in the diagram,
but let me write it out in symbols first.
在这个图里我会给你解释一下，但是让我先用符号把它写出来
The reason if, if you're given the output
of the cascade function applied to a
原因是，如果你有这个消息m的级联函数的的输出
message M. I can derive from it, me being
the adversary, I can derive from it the
我可以从它推导出，我作为敌手，我可以从它推导出
cascade applied to the message M
concatenated W for any message W, for any
消息m和任意消息w串接的级联函数值，任意w。
W. So first of all, it should be clear
that this is enough to mount an
首先，应该清楚，这个足以让我们推导出一个
existential forgery because essentially by
asking for a tag on this message I obtain
存在伪造，因为基本上，有这个消息的标签，我
the tag on this longer message which I can
then output as my forgery. Okay, so the
就可以得到这个长消息的标签，那我就能得到我的伪造了。
MAC is insecure because given a MAC in one
message, I can produce the MAC in another
好，所以这个MAC是不安全的，因为给出一个消息的MAC，我可以构造出另一个
message. But let's go back to the diagram
describing cascade, and see why this is
消息的MAC。但是让我们回来看一下这个描述级联的图，看一下为什么会这样
true. And so let's see what happens if
this last step isn't there. As an
让我们看一下如果这里没有这个最后一步会怎样。作为一个
attacker, what I can do, I can add one
more block here, which we called W. And
攻击者，我能做的是，我可以在这里加一个分组，我称它为w，接着
then, then basically, I can take the
output of cascade, which is this value T.
我用级联的输出这个值T
And we can simply apply the function F to
it again. So here I'll take this T value.
输入到函数F中，所以我把这个T输入到
I'll plug it in to F. And plug my last
block W into it and what I'll get is T
F，把我最后一个分组w也输入，这样我得到t'，
prime which is, well, the evaluation of
cascade on the message M concatenated W.
T'是消息m串接w的级联输出，
In [inaudible] calculated t prime, which I can use
for my existential forgery. Okay, so this
计算t',我就得到我的存在伪造。好
kind of shows you why this property of
cascade holes. This is called an extension
这个大概给你说明了，为什么级联是有漏洞的，这个称为
attack, Where giving a tag of the message
m I can deduce the tag for the extension
延展攻击，有消息m的标签，我可以推导出m的延伸消息的标签。
of m. And in fact for any extension of my
choice. So basically, Cascade is
实际上，我可以随我所愿进行延展。所以，本质上，级联函数式
completely insecure if we don't do this
last encryption step, and the last
完全不安全的。如果我们不做最后的这一步加密。最后的这一步
encryption step here basically prevents
this type of extension attack. I can tell
加密就是为了防止这种延展攻击的。我可以告诉大家
you by the way that in fact extension
attacks are the only attacks on a cascade
用这种方法延展攻击时级联方式的唯一攻击
and that could be made to precise. But I'm
not gonna do that here. The next question
可确定的。但是这里我就不说了。
is, why did we have the extra encryption
block in the ECBC construction? So again,
那接下来的问题是 我们为什么要在ECBC里面构造额外加密块呢
let me show you that without this extra
encryption block ECBC is insecure. So
让我再一次向你们说明 没有额外加密块的ECBC是不安全的
let's define a map that uses raw CBC. In
other words, it's the same as CBC MAC, but
我们用简化CBC定义一个映射 也就是说 跟CBC MAC一样
without the last encryption step. And
let's see that, that MAC is also insecure.
但是没有最后的加密步骤 我们来看 这个MAC依然不安全
Except now, the attack is a little bit
more difficult than a simple extension
除非是遭到一个比扩展攻击还难的攻击
attack. So suppose the attacker is given
this value, the raw CBC value for a
假设攻击者给定这个值 简化CBC M值为
particular message M. And now, the
attacker wants to extend and compute the
特定的消息 现在攻击者想要就一些
MAC on some message M, concatenated on
with some word W. So here's our W well the
与w串接的消息m对MAC进行扩展和计算 这是我们的w
core attacker can take this value and try
to XOR the two together but now you
而核心攻击者可以得到这个值 然后试图将它们两个异或到一起
realize he has to evaluate the function.
At this point. But he doesn't know what
但是你会意识到 他必须计算这个函数 此时他并不知道
this key K is. And as a result, he doesn't
know what the output of the function is.
密钥k是什么 因此 他也无法知道函数的输出是什么
So he simply can't just depend on
block W, and compute the value of
所以 他不能简单地依靠分组w  计算出简化CBC
raw CBC on N concatenated W. However, it
turns out that he can actually evaluate
对n串接w的值 最终他不能计算这个函数
this function. By using the chosen message
attack. And I wanna show you how to do
如果使用选择消息攻击 我来告诉你们怎么做
that. Okay, so we said that basically so
our goal is to show raw CBC is insecure.
我们说 我们的目标是说明简化CBC是不安全的
So let's look at a particular attack. So
in the attack, the adversary is going to
我们来看一个典型的攻击 在这个攻击里 对手将从
start by requesting the tag on a
particular message m that's a one-block
对一个特殊消息m请求标签开始 这是一个单分组消息
message. So what does it mean to apply CBC
to a one-block message? Well basically,
那把CBC应用到一个单分组消息是什么意思呢 事实上
all you do is you just apply the function
f directly. So what you get is the tag,
你们所做的仅仅是直接应用这个函数f 所以你们可以得到一个标签
which is just the application of f
directly to the one-block message m. Good,
刚好是f直接到单分组消息m的应用 好
so now the adversary has this value T. And
now I claim that he can define this
现在对手得到了t的值 我申明他可以定义这个消息为
message, M prime, which contains two
blocks. The first block is M, the second
m' 它包含两个分组 第一个分组是m 第二个
block is T XOR M. And I claim that the
value T that he just received is a valid
分组是t异或m 我申明他刚得到的t值是对m'的这两个
tag for this two block message, M Prime.
So let's see why that's true. Well, so
分组消息的有效标记 我们来看这为什么是正确的
suppose we apply the raw CBC construction
to this message M prime. So if you plug it
假设我们我们把这个简化CBC构造应用到这个消息m' 如果
in directly what, let's see. The way it
would work is first of all, the first
你把它直接加进去 它将计算第一个
message M is processed by encrypting it
directly using the function F. Then we XOR
消息m是直接用函数f进行加密的 然后
the results with the second block
with is T-XOR-M. And then we apply F to
我们将结果与第二个分组进行异或 然后我们
the results of that. That is the
definition of raw CBC. Now what do we know about
把f应用到刚才的结果上 这是简化CBC的定义 那现在
F(k,m)? F(k,m) is simply this value T by
definition. So the next step we get is
我们对F(k,m)了解多少呢 F(k,m)仅仅是定义中的t值 下一步
essentially T-XOR-T-XOR-M. But
this T- XOR-T simply goes away and what
我们要做的是t异或t异或m 但是这个t异或t没有作用
we get is F(k,m). Which is, of course, T.
And as a result, T is a valid MAC for the
我们将得到F(k,m) 也就是t 因此t是这个双分组消息的
two block message, (M, T-XOR-M). So
the adversary was able to produce this
一个有效MAC (M, T-XOR-M) 所以对手可以为这个
valid tag T for this two block message
that he never queried. And therefore, he
双分组消息制作一个标签 他不用查询 因此
was able to break the MAC. So let's look
at the ECBC diagram for just one more
他就能够成功攻击这个MAC 我们看一下这个ECBC图
second. And let me point out that if you
don't include this last encryption step in
我要指出的是 如果你们在MAC的计算中不使用
the computation of the MAC, essentially,
the MAC would be insecure because of the
最后这一步的加密 事实上 这个MAC将因为我们
attack that we just saw. And I'll tell you
that there are many products that do this
刚才讲到的攻击而不安全 我要说的是这样会有很多
incorrectly. And, in fact, there are even
standards that do this incorrectly, so
不正确的结果 事实上甚至有标准 这样做不正确
that the resulting MAC is insecure. You
now know that this needs to be done, and
这就是MAC不安全的原因 你们现在知道要做这个
you won't make this mistake yourself. So
let's state the CBC and NMAC security
并且你们自己不会犯这样的错误 我要声明CBC
theorems. And so the statement is as usual
for any message length that we'd like to,
和NMAC安全定理 这个声明同样对可以应用
apply the MAC to. Essentially for every
PRF adversary A, there's an efficient
这个MAC的任何消息长度有效 事实上对每个PRF对手A
adversary B and, you know, these are kind
of the usual statements. Where, the facts
有一个非常高效的对手B 你知道这有点像常用语句
that you need to know are the error terms
which are kind of similar in both cases.
事实上你要知道的是这些错误项在这两种情况下很相似
By the way, I'd like to point out that the
analysis for CBC actually uses the fact
另外 我要指出的是对CBC的分析其实本质是
that F is a PRP even though we never had
to invert F during the computation of
f是PRF 即使我们在计算ECBC时不会逆用f
ECBC, the analysis is better if you assume
that F is actually a PRP. In other words,
但是如果你假设f是PRF 这个分析会更好 也就是说
it's invertible, not just a function. For
a MAC, the PRF need not be invertible.
它是可逆的 而不仅仅是一个函数 对一个MAC PRF不需要是可逆的
So what these error terms basically say
is that these MACs are secure, as long as,
所以这些错误项本质上是说明这些MACs是安全的 就像
key is not used to MAC more than square
root of X or square root of K messages. So
密钥不像平方根的X或K消息的平方根那样多用于MAC
for AES of course this would be a two to
the 64. But I want to show you an example
所以对AES过程 这是2的64次方 我要给你们一个例子
of how you would use these bounds. So
here, I've stated the security theorem again
关于你们怎么运用这些边界 这里我要再一次声明
for the CBC MAC, and Q here, again, is the
number of messages that are MACed with a
关于CBC MAC的安全协议 这里的Q是被特定密钥MACed
particular key. So suppose we wanted to
ensure that for all adversaries that the
的消息数量 假设我们要像所有的对手验证
adversary has an advantage of less than
one over two to the 32 in distinguishing
敌手区分一个prf和真正随机函数的优势（可能性）
the PRF from a truly random function.
Suppose that is our goal. Well, by the
少于2的32次方分之一 假设这就是我们要做的
security theorem, what that means is we
need to ensure that Q squared over X is
根据安全定理 那意味着我们要证明 x绝对值分之q的平方
less than one over two to the 32, right.
We want this term to be, well, I'm going
少于2的32次方分之一 是的 我们希望这一项
to ignore this two here just for
simplicity. We want to ensure this term is
我准备忽略这两个以示讲解简略 我们要证明这一项比
less than one over two to the 32 and this
term, of course, is negligible, so we can
2的32次方分之一少 当然 这一项是可以忽略不计的 所以
just ignore it. This would imply that this
term is also less than one over two to the
我们只好忽略它 这就意味着它也比2的32次方分之一少
32. Okay, so if we want to ensure that the
advantage is less than one over two to the
好 如果我们要证明其优势少于2的32次方分之一
32, we need to ensure that Q squared over
X is less than one over two to the 32. For
那就是要证明x绝对值分之q的平方少于2的32次方分之一
AES, basically this means that after MACing
two to the 48 messages, you have to
对AES 这就意味着对2的48次方个消息做MAC后
change your key. Otherwise, you won't
achieve the security level. So you can
你必须更换你的密钥 否则的话 你将无法达到安全水平
MAC, at most, two to the 48 messages. You
notice that if I plug in triple DES, which
因此你最多只能MAC2的48次方个消息 你注意到如果我用三重DES
has a much shorter block, only 64 bits.
The same result says you now have to
它有很多短分组 仅仅64比特 结果同意告诉你
change your key every 65,000 messages. So
this basically is quite problematic
必须每65000个消息换一次密钥 然而 很麻烦的是
whereas this is fine. This is actually a,
a very fairly large number. For
这没有关系 这其实是一个相当巨大对的数目了
AES this means you have to change
your key only every 16 billion
对AES来说 你每160亿个消息只换一次密钥
messages which is perfectly reasonable.
And so this is one of the reasons why AES
是相当合理的 这就是AES具有比三重DES
has a larger block, than triple DES. Some of these modes remain
大的分组的原因之一 三重DES中的一些模式
secure and you don't have to change your
key as often as you would with triple
依然安全 你不必那样频繁的更换你的密钥
DES. Okay, so I want to show you
that in fact these attacks are not just in
所以我要告诉你们的是 事实上攻击者们在安全理论中
the statements in the security theorem, in
fact there really are real attacks that
不仅是这样的状态 其实真的存在真是的攻击者
correspond to these values. Now the macs
really do become insecure after you sign,
他们对应使用这些值 那这些MAC在你对x的平方根
you know, square root of X or square root
of K messages. So I'm going to show you an
或者k的平方根个消息签名之后将不再安全 我要
attack on both PRFs so either ECBC or
NMAC. Assuming that the underlying
给你讲一个对PRF的攻击 是ECBC或者NMAC 假设
function is a PRP, is actually a block
cipher like AES. Let's call F big, let's
这个下面的函数是个PRP 这其实就像是AES一样的分组加密 我们叫它F big
say that F big is either F ECBC or F NMAC.
So F big means that it's a PRF for large
我们说F big是F ECBC或F NMAC 所以F big是一个大消息的PRF
messages. Now, it turns out both
constructions have the following extension
结果这两种构造都具有以下扩展属性
property. Namely, if you give me a
collision. On messages X and Y. Then, in
也就是 如果你给我一个碰撞 向消息x和y
fact, that also implies a collision on an
extension of X and Y. In other words, if I
事实上 这也意味着对消息x和y的扩展的碰撞 换句话说
append W to both X and Y, I'll also get a
collision on the resulting words. So it's
如果我吧w同时附加在x和y上 我将完成一个对结果字的碰撞
fairly easy to convince yourself that this
extension property holds, you do it just
所以这相当容易使你自己坚信对扩展属性的持有 你
by staring at the diagram for a second.
And so imagine I give you two messages
只是看了这个图表几秒钟就做到了 想象我给你的
that happen to collide at this point. Now
remember, I assumed that F is a PRP. So
两个消息在这一点上发生碰撞 记住我假设f是一个PRP
once you fix K1, it's a one to one
function. So if the two messages happen to
所以一旦你固定k1 这就是一个1对1函数 如果这两个消息
map to the same value at the output. This
means they also happen to map to the same
在输出映射到同一个集合 这意味着它们在简化CBC里
value at the output of the raw CBC
function. But if they map to the same
输出也是映射到同一个集合 但是如果它们在简化CBC里
value at the output of the raw CBC
function, that means that if I add another
输出也映射到同一个集合 那就意味着然后我添加其他的分组
block, let's call it a W. And I take this
output here. Then I'm computing the same
姑且称之为w 我得到这个输出结果 计算出两个
value for both messages. And I'll get, for
both messages, I'll get the same value at
消息的值 我同样能得到这两个消息在这一点上
this point, too. And when I encrypt,
again, with K1, I'll also get, you know,
的相同值 当我再一次用k1加密时 我也会
so there's one more F here. I'll also get
the same output, final output, after I've
得到另外的一个f 以及相同的输出 最终的输出
appended the block W. Okay, so if the two
values happen to be the same for two
在我附加了分组w之后 所以一旦两个不同的消息
distinct messages. If I appended block W
to both messages, I'm still gonna get the
的值相同 如果我同时对两个消息附加了分组w 我同样会
same value out. It's easy to convince
yourself that the same is true for NMAC
得到相同的输出 这也使你相信 对NMAC 相同是对的
as well. Okay, so both of these, PRFs have
this extension property. So based on this,
这些PRP同时具有扩展属性 基于此
we can define an attack. So here's the
extension property stated again. And the
我们可以定义一个攻击 又是一个具有扩展属性的状态
attack would work as follows. Suppose I
issued square of Y chosen message
这个攻击工作如下 假设我选择以y的二分之一次方
queries. So, for AES, remember, the value
of Y is basically  to the 128. So this
发布信息的查询 对AES 要记得y的值是的128次方
would mean that I would be asking, two to
the 64 shows in message queries. For just
这意味着我要回应2的64次方的信息查询
arbitrary messages in the input space.
Well, what will happen is, I'll obtain,
对在输入空间中任意的消息 会发生的是 我会得到
well, I'll obtain two to the 64 message
MAC pairs. Now, we're gonna see in the
我会得到2的64次方个MAC消息对儿 我们来看下一个
next module, actually, there's something
called a birthday paradox. Some of you may
模块 事实上有一个理论称作生日悖论 你们中有人可能
have heard of it already. It basically
says that if I have two to the 64 random
已经听说过了 它讲的是如果你有2的64次方个随机元素
elements of a space of size two to the
128, there's a good chance that two of
存在于大小为2的128次方的空间 则其中两个元素相同
them are the same. So I'm gonna look for
two distinct messages. MU and MV, for
的概率会很大 我要找两个不同的消息 分别是Mu和Mv
which the corresponding MACs are the same.
Okay, and as I said, by the birthday
它们相对应的MAC相同 如我所讲 给予生日悖论
paradox, these are very likely to exist.
Once I have that, now I've basically found
这些很有可能存在 一旦我有了这些 就会发现
MU and MV to have the same MAC. And as a
result, what I can do is, I can extend MU
Mu和Mv有相同的MAC 因此 我可以根据生日悖论
with an arbitrary word W, and ask for the
tag for the word MU concatenated W. But
用w来扩展Mu 为Mu逻辑或w索要标签
because NU and NV happen to have the same
output, I know that NU concatenated W has
但是由于Nu和Nv也有相同的输出 那我可以得到Nu逻辑或w
the same output as NV concatenated W. So
now that I've obtained the output for NU
同Nv逻辑或w也有相同输出 因此我得到了Nu逻辑或
concatenated W, I also have the output for
NV concatenated W. And therefore I have
w的值 同时也得到了Nv逻辑或w的值 因此我得到了
obtained my forgery. Okay, so now T is
also a forgery for the message MV
我的伪码 现在t也是Mv逻辑或w的一个伪码
concatenated W which I've never asked
before. And therefore, this is as valid as
这是我之前从来没有要求过的 所以这跟潜在的
a potential forgery. Okay, so this is kind
of an acute attack and the bottom line
伪码一样有效 这是比较严重的攻击 最后一行
here is that in fact after square root of
Y queries, I am able to forge a MAC with
事实上是继y的平方根之后的查询 我可以
fairly good probability. Okay, so what
does square root of Y mean? If we go back
以相当大的概率打造一个MAC 那y的平方根有什么意义
to the security theorems, this means that
basically for ECBC after square root of X
我们回到安全定理 这意味着对于ECBC后x的平方根
or for NMAC after square root of K,
messages have been MACed, the MAC becomes
或者NMAC后k的平方根 消息已被MAC MAC变得
insecure and the attacker can actually
find new MACs for messages for which he
不安全 攻击者可以为他从来没有给MAC的消息
was never given a MAC for. So again, this
is an acute attack that shows the bounds
寻找新的MAC 同样 这是一个严重的感觉 说明
of the theorem really are real. And as a
result these downs that derived in this
边界的定理是真实的 因此这个例子里面的波动
example are real and you should never use
a single key to MAC more than, say, two
也是真实的 所以你不能再用单密钥去MACAES或CBC的
to 48 messages with AES based CBC. So to
conclude, I'll just mention that we've
超过2的48次方个消息 总结来看 我只提我们讲过的
seen two examples. We saw ECBC and NMAC.
ECBC is in fact, a very commonly used MAC
两个例子 来看ECBC和NMAC ECBC是一种常用的MAC
that's built from AES. 80211I, for example,
uses ECBC with AES for integrity.
是从AES衍生而来 举个例子 80211t 使用ECBC和AES的完整性
There's also a NIST standard called CMAC,
that we'll talk in the next segment, that
还有一个NIST标准叫做CMAC 我们下一节课会讲
also is based on the ECBC MAC. NMAC with
contrast is not typically used with a
也是基于ECBC MAC的 NMAC对比于分组加密中
block cipher. And the main reason is, in
order to [inaudible] in the NMAC construction,
并不常用 主要原因是 为了NMAC构造中的【不可闻性】
the key changes from block to block. That
means that the whole AES key expansion has
从一个分组到另一个分组的密钥更换 这意味着整个AES扩展
to be computed and recomputed on every
block. And AES is not designed to perform
不得不计算和重新计算每一个分组 AES要频繁的更换密钥
well when he changes key very rapidly. And
so, typically, when you use NMAC, you use
这一点设计的不好 所以 当你使用NMAC的时候 用分组加密
block ciphers that are better at changing
their keys on every block. And as a
比对每个分组更改密钥要好一些 因此
result, NMAC typically is not used with
AES. But in fact, N Mac is a basis of a
NMAC通常不跟AES一起用 不过 其实NMAC是一个
very popular MAC called HMAC, which we're
also gonna look at next. And you'll see
非常流行的MAC的基础 我们称其为HMAC 也会在下节课讲
very clearly, the NMAC underlying the HMAC construction. Okay, so that's the end
你会清楚地看到 NAMC下面的HMAC的构造是怎样的
of this segment, and we'll talk about more
MACs in the next segment.
好 这节课就到这里 我们下节课再讲更多的MAC